[NARRATOR]: Transcripts in a snap.
[snap]
Think of a transcript as a
text version of your video.
When made correctly,
video transcripts can
be read by screen readers
or turned into Braille documents,
making your content accessible
to people who are blind or low vision.
If a video player doesn’t support captions,
a transcript can provide access
for people who are Deaf and Hard of Hearing.
They're also helpful for people who
want to quickly scan
or search a video’s content.
So what’s in a transcript?
A basic transcript
is just a written version
of everything said in your video.
It also indicates who says it,
and any relevant sounds.
[clapping]
To make our transcripts more accessible,
make sure to include
any key visual information
someone would need
in order to understand
what’s going on,
such as locations or
important nonverbal communication.
How else would someone
relying on a transcript know
that your characters were
waving from a train?
[train whistle]
Many service providers will
transcribe your video for you
for less than a dollar a minute.
But if you’ve already done the work
to caption your video on youtube,
producing a video transcript
is a breeze.
First, navigate to the video on Youtube
and click the three-dot icon
just below the player
in the bottom right.
Select “Open Transcript”
from the drop-down menu
and a list of the video's captions will appear.
Remove the timestamps by clicking on
the three-dot icon
in the transcript toolbar,
and selecting “toggle timestamps”.
highlight all the text,
and copy and paste it into a document.
Add in important visual information where needed.
You can group lines together
by speaker if you like,
but it won’t make a difference
for people needing to access your content
using screen readers.
Its important to remember
that not all documents with text
are accessible.
Most PDFs, for instance,
“flatten” text into the document,
making it invisible to assistive screen readers.
So it’s best to save your transcript
as plain text
in a file type like .doc , .txt, or html.
After you’ve saved your transcript,
include a link to it
in your share text or on your website.
If you share your video on social media,
paste the transcript text
as the first comment on your post
so that users don’t have to click
to another page to access it.
Our goal here is accessibility,
and accessibility is cool.
Produced by Rooted in Rights.